bamboosolutions.com 2019-06-27

# Bamboo Solutions Privacy Policy - Bamboo Solutions

**Bamboo Solutions appreciates that your privacy and personal information are valuable to you.** This privacy policy tells you how Bamboo Solutions and its corporate parent, SharePointXperts, LLC, use your personal data when you visit our website, interact with us, and buy our goods and services.

It also tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

It is important that you read this privacy policy, together with any other privacy policies we may provide, so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data.

#### About Us and Important Information

In 2016 SharePointXperts, LLC acquired the ongoing assets of Bamboo Solutions. When we reference “Bamboo Solutions”, “we”, “us”, or “our” in the rest of this document, we are referring to the combined company and corporate parent SharePointXperts, LLC.  SharePointXperts, LLC is the controller and responsible for this website.

Our corporate mailing address and contact information are:

SharePointXperts, LLC

12110 Sunset Hills Road #600

Reston, VA 20190

sales@bamboosolutions.com

#### The Data We Collect About You

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).

We collect a variety of information about our customers (you!) and visitors to the Bamboo website. This personal data falls into these categories:

  * Identity Data includes first name, last name, username or similar identifier, and title.
  * Contact Data includes mailing address, email address and telephone numbers.
  * Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to access this website.
  * Profile Data includes your username and password, your interests, preferences and feedback.
  * Usage Data includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences.
  * Financial Data includes payment card details.
  * Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of products and services you have purchased from us.

We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy policy.

We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

Remember, if you choose not to share personal data with us, or refuse certain contact permissions, we might not be able to provide the products and services you’ve asked for.

#### How Your Personal Is Data Collected

**Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by mail, phone, email or through chat or social media.

This includes personal data you provide when you:

  * subscribe to our publications;
  * make enquiries or request information be sent to you;
  * create an account on our website;
  * order our products or services;
  * ask for marketing to be sent to you;
  * engage with us on social media;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * contact sales or support.

**Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with us, including via the Bamboo websites, we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We may also collect Tracking Data when you use our website, or when you click on one of our ads (including those shown on third party websites).

**Third parties or publicly available sources.** We may receive personal data about you from various types of third parties, including:

  * Technical Data and/or Tracking Data from analytics providers, advertising networks and search information providers;
  * Contact, Financial and Transaction Data from providers of payment and fraud prevention services;
  * Identity and Contact Data from data partners; and
  * Data from any third parties who are permitted by law or have your permission to share your personal data with us, such as via social media or review sites.

#### Legal Basis for Using Your Personal Data

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you. For example, when you purchase our products, that’s a contract.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation. For example, keeping a record of our sales for tax compliance.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than where the law requires it, for example in relation to sending certain direct marketing communications. Where our legal basis is consent, you have the right to withdraw consent any time.

#### How we use the data we collect

We process your personal information you provide us in strict accordance to this privacy policy. The purpose for collecting and using your personal data is with the aim of achieving three general objectives:

  1. To operate and deliver our business effectively (including personalization)
  2. To help us understand and improve our products and service, as well as the content we offer
  3. To send communications relevant to our users and products, as well as promotional communications where relevant

**Examples of data collection to improve and deliver our products and services:**

These examples help us achieve objectives one and two. To improve our user experiences, we use data we have collected across our websites, products and services.

To create and use a registered MyBamboo account, you must consent to these types of uses for your data, since we’re unable to deliver and operate your account without being able to collect this data.

  1. Product activation: creating your account or a free trial, or activating necessary software
  2. Product delivery: We use personal data to process payments and deliver our products to you. This might include saving your preferred user settings, or making product recommendations based on your device or current location.
  3. Customer support: We might use data to diagnose and fix product problems and issues, as well as provide more effective customer care.
  4. Improving our products and services: This includes improving our products as well as the information and content we provide on Bamboo websites.
  5. Security and safety: We must use data in order to protect the security of our products and users. This can include (but is not limited to) detection of fraud and malicious software, confirming validity of software licenses, and resolving disputes or enforcing our service agreement.
  6. General business intelligence: We use data to build up aggregated business intelligence to help us analyze, report on, and make informed decisions about our general business operations.

**Examples related to product communications using your personal data**

These examples help us to achieve objective three. You consent to receive these type of notifications from us by completing one of the contact forms on our website or registering an account with us.

You’re able to opt out from our mailing list by using the unsubscribe link at the bottom of any of our emails or by sending an email to sales@bamboosolutions.com.

  1. Sending Information to users with a registered MyBamboo account*: We may use your personal information in order to send any important notifications to communicate information necessary to the continued use of our products or services, including, but limited to: 
    1. Changes to our terms of service
    2. Changes to our privacy policy
    3. Product updates, upgrades, bug fixes, or other changes to your products or services
    4. Billing or payment information related to your use of your MyBamboo account

_*Because this information is important to your continued use of Bamboo products and services, you may not opt out of receiving these communications._

  1. Responding to requests for information: We may contact you via email or telephone where you have requested more information, for example booking a meeting, or to email you content you have asked to receive.

#### Marketing

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.

**Promotional offers from us**

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).

You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us or received services from us and, in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

**Opting out**

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us at sales@bamboosolutions.com.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a service provided to you.

#### Cookies

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly.

Cookies are data stored on the end-user’s hard drive with information that relates directly to the end-user’s visit to our web site. Any information placed in the cookie is accessible only to Bamboo Solutions, and will not be sold or shared with anyone else under any circumstances. We use a cookie to store a unique session identifier, which allows us to maintain shopping cart and web site selections from one page request to the next, and maintain session information from one visit to the next. By setting a cookie on our site, the user would not have to log in more than once, thereby saving time while visiting our site. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still browse our site. However, the user experience will be greatly curtailed. In addition, the user will be unable to log in or make a purchase. Cookies also enable us to track and target the interests of our users to enhance users’ experience and display products that relate directly to individual user preferences. None of our business partners and/or advertisers use cookies on our site.

#### Disclosure of Your Personal Data

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out in this privacy policy. We may also share your personal data if the law otherwise allows it.

We may share personal data with the following categories third parties:

  * Suppliers and service providers (such as technology service providers, payment processing and fraud prevention providers, manufacturers and post and courier services);
  * auditors and professional advisers like bankers, lawyers, accountants and insurers; and
  * government, regulators and law enforcement.

We also share data with third parties connected to advertising, retargeting and analytics. Please see Cookies above for more information about who those third parties are.

Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy notice.

We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

#### Payment information

Bamboo uses third party payment processors such as Recurly, PayPal, and Authorize.Net to process payments made for products and services via our website. All online payments will be conducted in accordance with Payment Card Industry (PCI) data security standards (which are high!) and your billing information (which is only used by these payment processors for the purpose of performing fraud protection) is encrypted before being communicated to them. Subject to the below exceptions, your credit card details are communicated directly from your browser to these payment processors – Bamboo never (ever!) sees your full Permanent Account Number (PAN). This means that the payment form is either off-site or displayed in a frame on the payment page.

For PayPal we only store the tokens required to identify the transaction with PayPal, issue refunds and identify transactions made using PayPal.

#### Data Security

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorized way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

#### Data Retention

We will only keep your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorized use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity, Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they stop being customers for tax purposes.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data; see Your legal rights below for further information.

In some circumstances we may anonymize your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

#### Your Legal Rights

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data. You have the right to:

  * **Request access to your personal data** (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * **Request correction of the personal data** that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * **Request erasure of your personal data.** This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * **Object to processing of your personal data** where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * **Request restriction of processing of your personal data**. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
  * **Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party**. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

_Updated May 24, 2018_
